

Richard Jamieson

Software Engineer

Contact

Address

Plettenberg Bay, South Africa 6600

Phone

+27 72 679 6818

E-mail

jamieson.rich@gmail.com

Skills

Solidity

Excellent

Javascript & NodeJS

Excellent

Python

Very Good

Ethers.js, Web3.js, Web3.py

Excellent

Tenderly, Hardhat, Truffle

Excellent

Git, Github

Very Good

Passionate and committed Smart Contract Developer with over 1.5 years of experience in the DeFi space, and prior experience in software development, finance and leadership of teams. Excellent reputation for collaborating in team environments to ship code that meets business requirements, is secure and gas efficient.

Recent Work History

2021-12 -Current

Solidity Developer

Opty.Fi, Remote

- Opty.Fi is a DeFi yield aggregation protocol on Ethereum and Polygon
- Worked as part of optimization engine team
- Employed machine learning techniques to optimize yield performance
- Built smart contract simulation and gas estimation engines in web3.py
- **Tech stack:** Solidity, TS, JS (inc ethers.js), Python (inc web3.py), Hardhat, Tenderly.

2021-07 -2022-07

Lead Solidity Developer

Crystl Finance, Remote

- Crystl Finance is a multi-chain vaulting protocol.
- Headed up the Solidity team
- Conceptualised and developed a V3 version of a set of vaulting smart contracts, which included several innovative features like boosted vaults and stacked vaults.
- Took V3 contracts through audit process with HashEx and into production on multiple EVM chains
- Tech stack: Solidity (inc some work in Assembly),
 TS, JS (inc ethers.js), Hardhat, Truffle.

2020-01 -2021-06

Co-founder & Lead Developer

Dalebrook Capital, Cape Town

- Dalebrook is a systematic quantitative investment fund, making use of multiple sources of data to drive investment decisions
- Built a back-testing engine and portfolio construction tool in Python (code can be viewed on Github), testing a universe of 500 stocks to generate a portfolio of 10.

Education

| 2000-01 - 2003-11 | Bachelor of Science: Electrical Engineering |
|----------------------|---|
| | University of Cape Town - Cape Town, South Africa Awarded Honours Degree Cum Laude Dean's List 2001, 2002, 2003 |
| 1997-02 - 1999-11 | Bachelor of Arts: Philosophy And Mathematics University of Cape Town - Cape Town, South Africa |